Robert Hillyer Papers
Robert Hillyer Papers
- Literary correspondence
  - Maxwell, William, 1932; 1938,; 1949,; undated; 11 Letters, 2 Cards (Box 4)
    Undated - ALS Appreciation of Hillyer's The Gates of the Compass.
    Undated - TLS Confirms publication of a Hillyer poem in The New Yorker and mentions Maxwell's completed novel.
    Undated - TLS Gives exact date for publication of Hillyer poem.
    Dec. - Signed Card. Mentions publication time of novel.
    31 Oct. 1932 - ALS Comments on Hillyer's Riverhead.
    25 Feb. 1938 - TLS Encloses check for Hillyer poem.
    14 Jun. 1949 - TLS Comments on Hillyer's articles concerning Ezra Pound, T. S. Eliot, et al.
  - McCord, David, 1961; 2 Letters (Box 4)
    4 Dec. 1961 - TLS Comments that he didn't realize that Hillyer disliked John Holmes' work. Despite this, he asks that Hillyer write a letter to support Holmes for Fellowship in the American Academy of Arts and Sciences. Congratulates Hillyer on his work in The New Yorker.
    15 Dec. 1961 - TLS Discusses his work and thanks Hillyer for writing about John Holmes. Discusses the omission of his poem "The Crows" in Untermeyer's latest anthology and comments on Hillyer's Fourth of July poem appearing in The New Yorker before his did.
  - McCreary, Fred, 1949; 2 Letters (Box 4)
    6 Jul. 1949 - TLS Mentions Robert Lowell and his interest in Ezra Pound's recordings. Congratulates Hillyer on his article on Ezra Pound in the Saturday Review of Literature.
    27 Jul. 1949 - ALS Comments on Robert Lowell's mild nervous breakdown. Mentions that Douglas Bush came for supper the night before.
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1959-1962; 13 Letters, 1 Telegram (Box 4)
    16 Jan. 1959 - TLS Executive Editor Edward Kuhn writes of his eagerness to publish a collection of Hillyer's best essays.
    5 Jun. 1959 - TLS Backed by Editor Kuhn, Associate Editor Gray Williams suggests that Hillyer write a prose work on poetry. The title for the book could be taken from one of Hillyer's addresses, "The Pursuit of Poetry." Williams also thinks that Hillyer's publisher Knopf would give Hillyer Option to do this book for McGraw-Hill.
    17 Jan. 1959 - TLS Editor Williams proposes drawing up contract for Hillyer to write the 70 to 80,000 word book In Pursuit of Poetry for spring publication.
    4 Apr. 1960 - TLS Editor Williams enjoyed reading Hillyer's book. Also encloses comments on criticisms. Asks if Hillyer wants to sign contract.
    10 Aug. 1960 - TLS Williams mentions that College Department at McGraw-Hill wants to do a text-edition of Hillyer's In Pursuit of Poetry. He says further that contract can be amended.
    11 Nov. 1960 - TLS Editor Kuhn describes McGraw-Hill's promotion plan for sale of Hillyer's book.
    11 Nov. 1960 - Telegram. Sent by Ed Kuhn congratulating Hillyer on publication day of In Pursuit of Poetry.
    20 Jun. 1961 - TLS Kuhn asks Hillyer to review manuscript of Jesse Stuart's poems.
    2 Oct. 1961 - TLS Leon Wilson sympathizes with Hillyer's disappointment with St. John. He comments that McGraw-Hill would like Hillyer to write his memoirs.
    16 Oct. 1961 - TLS Wilson elaborates more fully on plans for second Hillyer book.
    2 Nov. 1961 - TLS
    28 Dec. 1961 - TLS Leon Wilson expresses his personal sorrow to Mrs. Jeanne Hillyer upon hearing of Hillyer's death.
    23 Apr. 1962 - TLS Wilson promises Mrs. Hillyer that a decision will be made soon on Hillyer's material.
    11 May 1962 - TLS Wilson comments to Mrs. Hillyer that McGraw-Hill has lost a book because of Robert Hillyer's death.
  - Miles, Herbert Delahaye, 1949; 1 Letter (Box 4)
    23 Jul. 1949 - TLS Supports Hillyer position on Bollingen Award and mentions Leonie Adams' reactions to same.
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1940; 1 Telegram (Box 4)
    13 Nov. 1940 - Telegram. Refers to Ann Lindbergh's "insidious pamphlet" and states intention to publish reply.
  - Mills, Emma, 1949; 1954,; undated; 2 Letters, 1 Telegram (Box 4)
    Undated - Telegram. Congratulates Hillyer on his marriage.
    31 Jan. 1949 - ALS Encloses letter from Mollie Colum and comments on the Poetry Society Luncheon.
    19 Sept. 1954 - ALS Comments on Hillyer's move to Delaware.
  - Monroe, Harriet, 1936; 1 Letter (Box 4)
    1 Apr. 1936 - ALS Thanks Hillyer for support of student seeking admission to Harvard and mentions McCreary and Grant Code.
  - Moore, Marianne, 1941; 1949,; 1958; 6 Letters (Box 4)
    7 Dec. 1941 - TLS Discusses arrangements for poetry reading at Harvard.
    12 Dec. 1941 - ALS
    18 Dec. 1941 - ALS
    7 Feb. 1949 - TLS Agrees to read and criticize The Death of Captain Nemo.
    26 Sept. 1958 - TLS Agrees to second Hillyer's nomination of Howard Nemerov to National Institute of Arts and Letters.
    20 Oct. 1958 - TLS Mentions Hillyer's article "On Reading Verse Aloud."
  - Moore, Merrill, 1938; 1955; 2 Letters (Box 4)
    18 Nov. 1955 - TLS
  - Morton, David, 1939-1942; 1956; 6 Letters (Box 4)
    24 Feb. 1939 - ALS
    4 Apr. 1940 - ALS Mentions student Phil Young who will be studying under Hillyer.
    14 Jun. 1940 - ALS Mentions New Directions publications.
    31 Jul. 1941 - ALS
    1 Oct. 1942 - ALS Appreciation of Hillyer poem printed in New York Times.
    1 May 1956 - ALS Praises Hillyer's The Book of The Dead.
  - Morrison, S. E., undated; 1 Letter (Box 4)
    7 Dec. Undated - ALS Comments at length on Jensen's poem on Columbus.
  - Morrison, Ted, 1949; 1955,; 1962; 3 Letters (Box 4)
    2 Dec. 1949 - TLS Comments on The Death of Captain Nemo.
    1 Feb. 1955 - ALS
    4 Jan. 1962 - ALS Condolences to Mrs. Hillyer with reminiscence of years at Harvard under Hillyer; copies of Mrs. Hillyer's reply and Hillyer's original letter to author enclosed.
  - Moss, Howard, 1960; 1 letter (Box 4)
    8 Nov. 1960 - TLS Describes policy of returning manuscripts submitted to The New Yorker.
  - Mowrer, Paul Scott, 1959; undated; 3 Letters (Box 4)
    30 Sept. 1959 - TLS Thanks Hillyer for criticism and mentions May Sarton, Richard Wilbur, and manuscript of Mowrer's selected poems.
    11 Dec. 1959 - TLS Comments on Library of Congress lecture by Hillyer on Burns, by Richard Wilbur on Poe; and compares Hillyer to Frost.
    Undated - TS Poem for Hillyer in reply to remark of William Carlos Williams in a New York Times interview.
  - Munn, James B., 1936-1938; 1946,; 1949,; undated; 8 Letters (Box 4)
    Undated - ALS Appreciates Hillyer's Letter to Robert Frost and Other Poems and discusses science as a subject of great poetry.
    22 Sept. 1936 - ALS Compliments Hillyer on his book of Letters and accepts dedication of same.
    14 Oct. 1936 - ALS Comments on Hillyer's Letter to Bernard De Voto.
    14 Nov. 1936 - ALS Comments at length on Hillyer's Letter to My Son.
    7 Jan. 1937 - ALS Comments at length and analyzes Hillyer's Letter to Nefertiti.
    23 Nov. 1938 - ALS Analyzes elaborately Hillyer's "An Ode for the Alpha Chapter of Phi Beta Kappa."
    27 Nov. 1946 - ALS
    9 Jul. 1949 - ALS
  - Murdock, Kenneth, 1950; 1958,; 1960; 3 Letters (Box 4)
    16 Oct. 1950 - ALS Thanks Hillyer for invitation to visit Kenyon College and comments on that institution.
    16 Sept. 1958 - ALS Comments on unidentified Hillyer book.
    4 Jul. 1960 - ALS Discusses Hillyer's retirement.
  - Murray, Middleton J., 1926-1927; 4 Letters, 1 Card (Box 4)
    19 Dec. 1926 - ALS Discusses plan for future development of The Adelphi magazine and publication of Hillyer's "Prothalamion" therein.
    30 Jul. 1926 - ALS Discusses further publication of Hillyer's "Prothalamion" in The Adelphi as well as "Tierra del Fuego" and "The Strayed Minstrel."
    30 Jun. 1927 - TLS Mentions demise of The Adelphi magazine and plans for new quarterly The New Adelphi and requests that Hillyer review poetry for Same.
    4 Dec. 1927 - Card AS Appreciates Hillyer's abilities as a poetry critic.
  - Nathan, Robert, 1929; 1949-1950,; 1960-1961; 7 Letters (Box 4)
    17 Jun. 1929 - TLS Compliments Hillyer on his articles concerning Pound and Eliot.
    25 Jun. 1949 - TLS
    9 Aug. 1949 - ALS Appreciates The Death of Captain Nemo.
    22 Mar. 1950 - ALS
    2 Aug. 1960 - TLS Mentions nomination of Jesse Stuart.
    8 Aug. 1961 - TLS Discusses and describes Nathan's forthcoming unidentified book.
  - Neale, J. E., 1934; 1 Letter (Box 4)
    17 Feb. 1934 - ALS Thanks Hillyer for comments and invites him to visit.
  - Neihardt, John, 1928; 1949,; 1954,; 1960; 5 Letters (Box 4)
    23 Mar. 1928 - TLS
    13 Aug. 1949 - TLS
    13 Sept. 1949 - ALS Detailed appreciation of The Death of Captain Nemo.
    11 Sept. 1954 - ALS Promises to vote for Oliver St. John Gogarty for prize.
    6 Aug. 1960 - ALS
  - Nemerov, Howard, 1947; 1954-1955,; 1957-1961; 29 Letters (Box 4)
    1 Apr. 1947 - ALS Criticizes popular magazines and their policies.
    9 Dec. 1954 - TLS Praises Hillyer's influence.
    30 Sept. 1955 - TLS Request Hillyer's support to receive Guggenheim Grant.
    19 Feb. 1957 - TLS Discusses attitudes towards forthcoming unnamed book and life in general.
    30 Sept. 1958 - TLS Comments on current literary activity and mentions new position at University of Minnesota.
    8 Oct. 1958 - TLS Discusses Nemerov's proposed entry into The National Institute of Arts and Letters.
    14 Feb. 1959 - TLS Mentions literary activity and outcome of nomination to The National Institute of Arts and Letters; expresses opinion on outcome of current National Book Award competition.
    28 Feb. 1959 - TLS Discusses book of short stories A Commodity of Dreams and mentions St. John Perse, Archibald MacLeish's JB, National Book Award, Dudley Fitts, Billy Abrahams.
    25 Mar. 1959 - TLS Discusses poem "Runes" and analyzes James Wright.
    18 Apr. 1959 - TLS Comments at length on Lionel Trilling; criticizes astronomy; discusses relationship with The New Yorker magazine, and compliments Hillyer on his "Manorbier" and The Death of Captain Nemo.
    14 May 1959 - TLS Discusses forthcoming publication of essays and comments on future literary activity; recounts meeting with Robert Frost.
    27 Oct. 1959 - TLS Describes author's health.
    10 Dec. 1959 - TLS Comments on Burns' and Hillyer's work.
    31 Dec. 1959 - TLS Discusses The Next Phase and mentions New and Selected Poems.
    24 Jan. 1960 - TLS
    2 Mar. 1960 - TLS Discusses Hillyer's request of University of Delaware officials that Nemerov be named his successor.
    28 May 1960 - TLS Describes Nemerov's present state of despair and analyzes its roots.
    18 Jun. 1960 - TLS Mentions total sale of last book and grants Hillyer reprint permission for special project.
    20 Jul. 1960 - TLS Comments on play commissioned by Union Theological Seminary entitled Endor and comments further on Hillyer's offer to review New and Selected Poems for the New York Times.
    5 Nov. 1960 - TLS Mentions unnamed new book and comments on report of Faculty-Trustee committee of Bennington College.
    29 Nov. 1960 - TLS Mentions possible paper-back edition of New and Selected Poems and praises unnamed Hillyer book.
    24 Jan. 1961 - TLS Comments on review by Kenneth Rexroth of Nemerov's new book and quotes letter sent in reply.
    27 Feb. 1961 - TLS Mentions letter in reply to Rexroth's review and award by National Institute of Arts and Letters.
    16 Mar. 1961 - TLS Describes musical avocation and mentions Gottfried Benn, Edwin Muir, The Bachelors by Muriel Spark, Graham Greene, Mark Watson, and Billy Abrahams.
    3 Apr. 1961 - TLS Acknowledges book sent by Hillyer and comments on "Manorbier."
    10 Apr. 1961 - TLS Discusses Hillyer's Collected Poems at length and encloses carbon copy of letter to Mark Watson on Hillyer.
    22 Jul. 1961 - TLS Mentions projected trip to Salzburg and current literary activity.
    25 Dec. 1961 - TLS Condolences to Mrs. Hillyer.
  - Nicholl, Louise Townsend, 1953; 1955-1956,; undated; 9 Letters (Box 4)
    Undated - TLS Thanks Hillyer for complimentary review and philosophizes on the writing of poetry.
    Undated - AL Reminiscences about life in general.
    16 Oct. 1953 - ALS Mentions Tommy Sloane and Kimball Flaccus.
    3 Jan. 1955 - ALS
    1 Aug. 1955 - TLS
    30 Sept. 1955 - TLS Discusses current financial situation and thanks Hillyer for having obtained award for her.
    31 Jul. 1956 - ALS
    8 Aug. 1956 - TLS
    10 Aug. 1956 - TLS Sends Water and Light and Dawn in Snow and comments on early writing career.
  - Norman, Charles, 1958; 3 Letters (Box 4)
    18 Feb. 1958 - TLS Mentions unnamed book in which Hillyer is included in the "Harvard" and "Eight Harvard Poets" chapters.
    3 Mar. 1958 - TLS Requests permission to publish Hillyer letter concerning author's "Eight Harvard Poets."
    6 Mar. 1958 - TLS
  - O'sheel, Shaemas, 1949; 1 Letter (Box 4)
    19 May 1949 - TLS Discusses at length possible reasons for which Ezra Pound wrote Pisan Cantos and the relationship of the Bollingen and Nobel Awards to Fascist revival.
  - Parker, Elinor, 1962; 1 Letter (Box 4)
    2 Apr. 1962 - TLS Requests permission for use of Hillyer's "The Dead Man Ariseth And Singeth a Hymn To the Sun" from The Book of The Dead in an anthology to be entitled The Singing And The Gold.
  - Perry, Bliss, 1934-1935; 1940-1941,; 1944,; 1946,; 1950; 8 Letters (Box 4)
    8 May 1934 - ALS Informs Hillyer that he has won the Pulitzer Prize by a unanimous vote.
    12 Oct. 1935 - ALS
    14 Dec. 1940 - ALS Compliments Hillyer on unidentified book of poetry.
    14 Feb. 1941 - ALS Comments on W. H. Auden's talent and expresses dissatisfaction with The Atlantic magazine.
    27 Dec. 1944 - ALS Encloses copy of Lucien Price's editorial and mentions transfer from Williams to Princeton.
    22 May 1946 - ALS
    21 Dec. 1946 - ALS
    23 Dec. 1950 - ALS Describes health.
  - Pinkham, Daniel, 1961; 1 Letter (Box 4)
    3 Nov. 1961 - TLS Discusses publication of two Hillyer poems in choral settings created by Pinkham.
  - Raines, Claude, 1953; undated; 1 Letter, 2 Cards (Box 4)
    [Illegible date] - Signed Card. Mentions state of movie business.
    [Illegible date] - Signed Card.
    31 Mar. 1953 - TLS Contemplates notion of including Hillyer's The Death of Captain Nemo in his lecture tour.
  - Rascoe, Burton, 1940; 1 Letter (Box 4)
    2 Mar. 1940 - TLS Discusses Dial literary squabble.
  - Reedy, William Marion, 1920; 1 Letter (Box 4)
    4 Jun. 1920 - TLS Appreciates Hillyer's Five Books of Youth.
  - Reese, Lizette, 1922-1923; undated; 5 Letters (Box 4)
    Undated - ALS Congratulates Hillyer on his marriage.
    18 Aug. 1922 - ALS Congratulates Hillyer on acquisition of home.
    24 Aug. 1922 - ALS Inquires whether Bruce Rogers is a publisher or printer.
    17 Oct. 1923 - ALS Encloses copy of Wild Cherry.
    9 Nov. 1923 - ALS Thanks Hillyer for compliments on Wild Cherry.
  - Reppelier, Agnes, 1936; 4 Letters (Box 4)
    19 Mar. 1936 - ALS Thanks Hillyer for compliments on her Horace.
    21 Jun. 1936 - ALS
    27 Jul. 1936 - ALS Mentions Hillyer's A Letter to Robert Frost and Others and Santayana.
    7 Aug. 1936 - ALS Describes Santayana's personal attitude towards Harvard and comments on his financial condition.
  - Richards, Laura E., 1935; 4 Letters (Box 4)
    11 Nov. 1935 - ALS Thanks Hillyer for considering author's unnamed article for the Harvard Press.
    25 Nov. 1935 - ALS Inquires about book sent by author to Hillyer.
    3 Dec. 1935 - ALS
    5 Dec. 1935 - ALS Further inquiry about book.
  - Richardson, Bruce, 1944; 1 Letter (Box 4)
    5 Jan. 1944 - TLS Expresses regret and joy at Hillyer's decision to leave Harvard and asks who new Boylston. professor will be.
  - Richter, Conrad, 1949; 1 Letter (Box 4)
    12 Aug. 1949 - TLS Congratulates Hillyer on his attack on Fellows of the Library of Congress.
  - Roberts, Kenneth, 1949; 1961; 6 Letters (Box 4)
    22 Apr. - ALS Mentions Hillyer's review of Robert's work in The New York Times.
    16 Mar. 1949 - TLS Comments on uncompleted book of which Hillyer has been sent galley proofs; mentions National Institute of Arts and Letters.
    7 May 1949 - TLS Discusses Hillyer's attack on Pound and comments on Bollingen Award; mentions Hillyer's reviews.
    21 May 1949 - TLS Encloses excerpts from a report on the Fellows of the Library of Congress.
    24 Jun. 1949 - TLS Encloses Letter from Robert Hale concerning Fellows of the Library of Congress.
    15 Aug. 1949 - TLS Compliments Hillyer on The Death of Captain Nemo.
  - Roberts, Ruby Altizer, 1949; 1961; 2 Letters (Box 4)
    7 May 1949 - TLS Announces award of one thousand dollars to Hillyer from The Lyric Associates, Inc., Foundation.
    29 Dec. 1961 - TLS Condolences to Mrs. Hillyer.
  - Robinson, Corinne Roosevelt, 1932; 1 Letter (Box 4)
    10 Feb. 1932 - ALS
  - Robinson, Lenox, 1932; 1936,; 1947,; 1949,; undated; 8 Letters, 2 Cards (Box 4)
    Undated - Poem to Robert Hillyer with holograph addendum.
    7 Dec. 1932 - TLS Inquires about Hillyer's novel and mentions Yeats.
    Apr. 1932 - Poem to Robert Hillyer inscribed.
    3 May 1932 - TLS Congratulates Hillyer on success of his novel and mentions Yeats; also describes Robinson's activities.
    Dec. 1936 - Signed Card.
    31 Jan. 1936 - TLS Comments on Hillyer's novel and encloses appeal.
    12 Dec. 1947 - TLS Mentions Hillyer's new book. Signed Card.
    25 Dec. 1949 - Signed Card.
  - Roethke, Theodore, 1942; undated; 1 Letter, 1 Card (Box 4)
    8 Apr. 1942 - ALS Discusses Roethke's book to which Hillyer wrote introduction; mentions Hillyer's poem published in Vice Versa.
    Undated - Signed Card. Thanks Hillyer for letter about poem "The Waking;" card includes poem "The Restored."
  - Rollins, Hyder Edward, 1958; 2 Letters (Box 4)
    26 Mar. 1958 - ALS Discusses Harvard and the English department.
    6 May 1958 - ALS Mentions work on Keats and suggests that Hillyer try to review it for The New York Herald-Tribune or The Saturday Review of Literature.
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, Jr., 1938; 1941; 2 Letters (Box 4)
    10 Oct. 1938 - TLS Explains financial condition and regrets inability to subscribe to appeal of Hillyer's.
    31 May 1941 - ALS Promises to expedite transfer of unnamed friend of Hillyer.
  - Rosenfeld, Paul, 1927-1928; 1932; 7 Letters (Box 4)
    22 Jan. 1927 - TLS Praises Hillyer's fantasy The Happy Episode and requests that he send the rest of the chapters.
    28 Jan. 1927 - TLS Discusses at length problems pertaining to Hillyer's short fantasy The Episode and explains why it will be difficult to get it published.
    1 Mar. 1927 - ALS Praises last four chapters of Hillyer's The Happy Episode with special praise for Chapter Seven.
    5 Jul. 1928 - TLS Announces change in publication dates for The Caravan and presses Hillyer to prepare something for it.
    13 Oct. 1928 - TLS Describes and comments on evening in Boston with Hillyer, S. Foster Damon and others.
    18 Nov. 1928 - TLS Mentions marked similarity between Hillyer's and Sherwood Anderson's criticism of his novel and analyzes Hillyer's sonnet sequence at length.
    24 Oct. 1932 - TLS
  - Roskolenko, Harry, 1949; 1 letter (Box 4)
    14 Jun. 1949 - TLS Agrees with Hillyer's article in The Saturday Review of Literature on Ezra Pound.
  - Russell, Ada D., 1929; 1 Card (Box 4)
    17 Dec. 1929 - Signed Card. Praises Hillyer's poem "The Ode."
  - Russell, A.E., 1931; 1 Letter (Box 4)
    24 Jan. 1931 - ALS
  - Sherwood, Robert E., 1952; 1 Letter (Box 4)
    16 Jan. 1952 - TLS Sherwood expresses his pleasure that Hillyer has been asked to write a Time magazine article on him. Discusses possible date of their meeting.
  - Sandburg, Carl, 1942; 1958; 2 Letters, 1 Telegram (Box 5)
    12 Mar. 1942 - TLS Regrets inability to accept speaking engagement.
    6 May 1942 - Telegram. Confirms unnamed engagement.
    14 Nov. 1958 - TLS Mentions author's enjoyment of Hillyer's letters and Pound controversy.
  - Santayana, George, 1923; 1 Letter (Box 5)
    9 Nov. 1923 - ALS Explains in detail why it was necessary to make a change in a sonnet of his which Hillyer preferred in the original version.
  - Sarton, May, 1955; 1 Card (Box 5)
    6 Feb. 1955 - Signed Card. Praises unnamed lyric of Hillyer's.
  - Sassoon, Siegfried, 1960; 1 Letter (Box 5)
    10 Feb. 1960 - ALS Grants Hillyer right to quote from author's "Everyone Sang," mentions current literary projects; discusses Hillyer's review of Sequences.
  - Schorer, Mark, 1942; 1955-1956; 8 Letters and 1 Card (Box 5)
    1942 - TLS Encloses copy of unnamed book and tells of plans to have book turned into a play and/or scenario by Hollywood writer Lynn Starling.
    1942 - TLS Describes California; discusses writer Lynn Starling and his work on dramatization of Schorer's book; comments on Grahame Greene.
    2 Feb. 1942 - TLS
    22 Feb. 1942 - TLS Praises Hillyer's new novel; comments further on Mr. Lynn Starling's dramatization of book; thanks Hillyer for information on Harvard speed-up plan.
    8 May 1942 - TLS Mentions Hillyer's difficulties with his eyes and discusses Hillyer's interpretation of Schorer's article in The Advocate.
    20 May 1942 - TLS
    14 Dec. 1955 - TLS Regrets the ending of their correspondence and compliments Hillyer on his poem in the New York Times Book Review.
    25 Jul. 1956 - ALS Comments on Japan.
  - Scott, Evelyn, 1938; 3 Letters (Box 5)
    1 May 1938 - TLS Discusses existing conditions affecting freedom of the press.
    8 May 1938 - ALS Comments further on freedom of the press with specific mention and analysis of the role played by Malcolm Cowley in creating public attacks; mentions Granville Hicks.
    29 May 1938 - TLS Praises Hillyer's poems and describes and contradicts scandal spread concerning Emma Goldman; mentions warning given to her by Communist Party members to stop criticizing the party in print or expect boycott of her writing.
  - Scott, Winfield Townley, 1957-1961; 12 Letters (Box 5)
    6 Mar. 1957 - TLS Thanks Hillyer for favorable review of his book and discusses certain of Hillyer's criticisms.
    12 Sept. 1957 - TLS Agrees to write essay on Hillyer if Clarence Decker so desires.
    7 Jan. 1957 - TLS Describes background material Clarence Decker loaned author as basis for article on Hillyer.
    23 Sept. 1957 - TLS Mentions receiving a copy of Hillyer's The Relic and Other Poems and asks advice on research for an article on Hillyer.
    2 Oct. 1957 - TLS Discusses the development of essay on Hillyer and refers to the Scott Lecture No. 1, The Relic and Other Poems, and A Letter to Robert Frost and Others as bases for his essay.
    26 Sept. 1958 - TLS Discusses published article on Hillyer.
    5 Oct. 1958 - Card Congratulates Hillyer on "The Graveyard Poem" appearing in The Atlantic Monthly.
    10 Jan. 1959 - TLS Comments on second Hillyer review of The Dark Sister.
    14 May 1959 - TLS Praises Hillyer's "Eppur Si Muove" and describes projected book to be entitled Scrimshaw; mentions Witter Bynner, Malcolm Cowley, Harold Loeb, William S. Braithwaite, the Trillings, and A. E. Ficke.
    1 Oct. 1959 - TLS Thanks Hillyer for reviewing The Dark Sister a second time.
    16 Apr. 1960 - TLS Discusses Hillyer's review of book Scrimshaw.
  - Shepard, Odell, 1923; 1925; 3 Letters (Box 5)
    16 Apr. 1923 - TLS Expresses dissatisfaction with life at Trinity College.
    16 Jun. 1925 - TLS Offers Hillyer teaching position at Trinity College and expresses his strong preference for Hillyer over other possible candidates.
    Aug. 1925 - TLS Encloses poem entitled "To Ariel and Miranda for Showing Me the Wonders of the Isle."
  - Simpson, Louis, 1949; 2 Letters (Box 5)
    7 Dec. 1949 - TLS Requests that Hillyer recommend him for the position of Junior Fellow at Harvard.
    19 Dec. 1949 - TLS Gives Hillyer basic information about procedure for making recommendation for Junior Fellow and explains his reasons for desiring to study at Harvard.
  - Smith, Harrison, 1949-1950; 6 Letters (Box 5)